<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Optimization Modeling for Store Product Clustering and EOQ Determination</title>
      <link>https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/notes/2020/optimization_modeling_for_store_product/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/notes/2020/optimization_modeling_for_store_product/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Problem Statement The objective of this study is to develop a robust optimization solution that enables the determination of an optimal replenishment for managing store products. By doing so, store managers can gain valuable insights into the ideal stock levels required to meet customer demand while minimizing holding costs and ensuring efficient inventory management practices. The approach outlined in this article demonstrates the potential to enhance inventory management practices within a retail chain, empowering store managers with accurate and data-driven decision-making capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weighted-Least-Square</title>
      <link>https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/notes/2020/2019-10-30-weighted-least-squares/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/notes/2020/2019-10-30-weighted-least-squares/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Nowadays, having a business implies օwning a website. The primary aim of a website is to provide information, which is crucial in the modern business world. Suppose a website owner aims at increasing the number of visitors in order to have more views, sales or popularity. To achieve this goal, one first needs to understand the factors affecting web traffic. The vast majority of small businesses try to increase website hits or visits via advertisements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weighted-Least-Square</title>
      <link>https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/post/2020/jan/2019-10-30-weighted-least-squares/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/post/2020/jan/2019-10-30-weighted-least-squares/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Nowadays, having a business implies օwning a website. The primary aim of a website is to provide information, which is crucial in the modern business world. Suppose a website owner aims at increasing the number of visitors in order to have more views, sales or popularity. To achieve this goal, one first needs to understand the factors affecting web traffic. The vast majority of small businesses try to increase website hits or visits via advertisements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shapley Value Regression</title>
      <link>https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/notes/2020/2019-12-20-shapley-value-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/notes/2020/2019-12-20-shapley-value-regression/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In marketing research, the problem of multicollinearity can be raised as a result of using clients&amp;rsquo; rating responses. People tend to answer to the question of some section/topic in relatively same way. The stronger the correlations between the explanatory variables, the larger the population variances of the distributions of their coefficients, and thus greater the risk of obtaining unreliable coefficients. Although the estimated coefficients will be unbiased, their high variance will decrease the $t$ value, which leads to the failure in rejecting the null hypothesis $H_0:\beta = 0$, and following reduction in the probability of correctly detecting a non-zero coefficient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes in air pollution</title>
      <link>https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/notes/2020/2020-01-09-changes-in-air-pollution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/notes/2020/2020-01-09-changes-in-air-pollution/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Even without visible smog, air pollution is all around us, and thus it is hard to eliminate the health effects of the toxic contaminators on health. The harmful effect of air pollutants is widely investigated in different researches conducted in many regions of the world. Air pollutants can be the cause of death from stroke, lung cancer, and another heart disease. Air pollution has a pernicious effect on children and it trigger childhood cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outlier Detection in Air Pollution Data</title>
      <link>https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/notes/2020/2019-11-15-outlier-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/notes/2020/2019-11-15-outlier-detection/</guid>
      <description>Introduction On a daily basis, economical, technological and political changes cause air pollution, which is currently one of the most pressing environmental issues around the globe. It is particularly acute in large cities with the rising level of industrialization and growing urbanization. The polluted air we breathe results in serious health disorders and decreases the quality of life. Before steps are taken to decrease the harmful effect of daily produced pollutants, certain measurements are required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propensity-Score-Matching</title>
      <link>https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/notes/2020/2019-10-15-propensity-score-matching/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/notes/2020/2019-10-15-propensity-score-matching/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The research question is whether playing chess is correlated with the improvement in logical thinking. Previous research, conducted in a number of countries , indicates that playing a game of chess increases concentration, logical and critical thinking, as well as the ability to plan and analyse.
Should one aim at increasing the level of logical thinking among university students and schoolchildren by playing chess, the following steps are to be taken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimization Modeling for Store Product Clustering and EOQ Determination</title>
      <link>https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/notes/2020/new-folder/artilce_upd_06_07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/notes/2020/new-folder/artilce_upd_06_07/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Problem Statement The objective of this study is to develop a robust optimization solution that enables the determination of an optimal replenishment for managing store products. By doing so, store managers can gain valuable insights into the ideal stock levels required to meet customer demand while minimizing holding costs and ensuring efficient inventory management practices. The approach outlined in this article demonstrates the potential to enhance inventory management practices within a retail chain, empowering store managers with accurate and data-driven decision-making capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
