<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Experimental Studies on </title>
    <link>https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/tags/experimental-studies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Experimental Studies on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/tags/experimental-studies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Optimization Modeling for Store Product Clustering and EOQ Determination</title>
      <link>https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/notes/2020/optimization_modeling_for_store_product/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/notes/2020/optimization_modeling_for_store_product/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Problem Statement The objective of this study is to develop a robust optimization solution that enables the determination of an optimal replenishment for managing store products. By doing so, store managers can gain valuable insights into the ideal stock levels required to meet customer demand while minimizing holding costs and ensuring efficient inventory management practices. The approach outlined in this article demonstrates the potential to enhance inventory management practices within a retail chain, empowering store managers with accurate and data-driven decision-making capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propensity Score Matching</title>
      <link>https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/notes/2020/2019-10-15-propensity-score-matching/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://DatamotusBlog.netlify.app/notes/2020/2019-10-15-propensity-score-matching/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The research question is whether playing chess is correlated with the improvement in logical thinking. Previous research, conducted in a number of countries , indicates that playing a game of chess increases concentration, logical and critical thinking, as well as the ability to plan and analyse.
Should one aim at increasing the level of logical thinking among university students and schoolchildren by playing chess, the following steps are to be taken.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
